Joshua Pena

23246 Calle Nogales Apt 262, Moreno Valley CA, 92557 josh.uapena20002@gmail.com | (951) 941-6071

Github Replit | LinkedIn

Objective

I am interested in research positions at MSRIP for Transfers with Dr. Eldawy and Dr. Medina. My interest in GIS, AI, and creative and programming skills enables me to solve problems related to research questions. This helps the researchers achieve considerable progress in their field.

Skills

- C++, Python, HTML, Java, Assembly
- Raspberry PI, soldering PCB electronics
- Replit Database, Flask
- Critical thinking
- Problem solving
- Interpersonal communication
- Data Entry
- Data Analysis
- Fluent in English & Spanish; Conversational French

Job History

CNAS Graduate Student Affairs Center | University of California, Riverside

October 2023 | Office Assistant

- Upload over 200 graduate student employment documents using UCR's TAOnline database system.
- Filter all applicants for 30 different CNAS scholarships using Blackbaud's conditions on student metrics.
- Validate student data for over 400 GSRs and TAs in every CNAS department using csv files.

Moran Management and Consulting, Inc. | Moreno Valley, CA

January 2023 - April 2023 | Recruiter Support Specialist

- Pre-screened an average of 20 potential employees for interviews daily.
- Maintained a spreadsheet of over 100 applicants to fill job orders.
- Called an average of 15 applicants for in-person interviews with recruiters.
- Reported daily and weekly number of calls to supervisors for evaluations.

Moreno Valley College - First Year Experience (FYE) | Moreno Valley, CA

May 2021 - June 2022 | Student Aide I (FYE Peer Leader)

- Led quarterly workshops in-person and through Zoom for students in FYF.
- Conducted weekly orientations and tours for new students in the program.
- Responded to more than 50 phone calls and emails sent by students daily.
- Collaborated with other Peer Leaders to complete weekly projects for the program.

Projects

5-Draw Poker in C++

- Implemented logic for ranking 10 types of hands in Poker.
- Wrote logic and 3 cases for a simple AI for the user to play against.
- Organized gameplay flow for multiple playthroughs.

Top Songs of the Year ft. Spotify API in Python

- Connected Spotify's API to Replit's Flask for webview.
- Designed the webview using HTML and CSS.
- Organized data using json formatting.

Private Journal with Login System in Python

- Used Replit's database tool to store user login data.
- Implemented login system to a secure private journaling program.
- Connected Replit's login authentication to the login system.

Education

Moreno Valley College | Moreno Valley, CA | August 2020 - June 2023

- Associates in Science, Mathematics for Transfer GD
- Associates in Science, Computer Science for Transfer GD
- Associates in Arts, Social and Behavioral Sciences GD
- Associates in Arts, Humanities, Philosophy and Arts GD
- Dean's List (Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Summer 2021)

Coursework

- Software Construction
- Probability and Statistics for Engineering
- Technical Communications
- C++ Discrete Structures
- C++ Data Structures
- Differential Equations
- Linear Algebra

Professional References

Seabrook Mendoza | Employment and Scholarship Specialist CNAS Graduate Student Affairs Center, University of California, Riverside

• seabrook@ucr.edu

Edward F. Alvarez | Dean of Student Services

Victor Valley Community College

• edward.alvarez@vvc.edu

Melissa Lopez | Enrollment Services Assistant

Moreno Valley College

• melissa.lopez@mvc.edu